Guide to the Ernest J. Sternglass papers, [ca. 1952-2008]
Sternglass, Ernest J. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ernest J. Sternglass papers, [ca. 1952-2008]
6842
Ernest J. Sternglass
111 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Notebooks, correspondence, clippings, and subject files relating to Sternglass's interests..
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Physicist.
Ernest Joachim Sternglass (born 1923) came to the United States in 1938. He received a Bachelor's degree in Electrical Engineering from Cornell in 1944 and and M.S. and Ph.D. in Applied & Engineering Physics in 1951 and 1953. From 1952 to 1967, he worked at the Westinghouse Research Laboratory on nuclear instrumentation, especially fluoroscopy, and he was the lead scientist for its Lunar Station program. His work allowed for the live viewing of the Apollo 11 moon landing. Beginning in the early 1960s he became interested in the health risks of low-level radiation from nuclear testing and nuclear power plants. He was the co-founder and director of the Radiation and Public Health Project. His work on X-rays advanced the field of safer digital imaging, reducing patients exposure to radiation. He became a professor at the University of Pittsburgh and has also written on cosmology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Notebooks, correspondence, clippings, and subject files relating to Sternglass's interests, especially the health effects of low-level radiation, cosmology, and the history of science. Includes files about the accident at the Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sternglass, Ernest J.; Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.); University of Pittsburgh--Faculty.; Westinghouse Electric Corporation.Research Laboratories.
Subjects:
Low-level radiation--Health aspects--United States.; Radioactive pollution--Toxicology.; Radiation--Toxicology.; Radiation--Physiological effect.; Environmental health.; Health risk assessment.; Nuclear power plants--Accidents.; Cosmology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Alphabetical File List
  - Alberson, Philip. H, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertisements. Nuclear and utility Industries., 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aging and Radiation. Animals and Man, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aging and Radiation Mechanism., 1961-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aging Research at university of Pittsburgh, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "AIDS - related Mortality Trends" Buehler, J.N. et al. AJPH 80, 1080 (1990) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Airborne Radioactivity Measurements, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Air Pollution - Allegheny County, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Air Pollution. Evidence for Death Rates and Radioactivity Increase. Snow, Acid Rain., 1964-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Air Pollution Standards and Levels (US, PIGH). Acid Rain, SO2, NO., 1969-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alaska - Infant Mortality (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alaskan (Amchitka) Test and Effects on Carribou (USSR and China), 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alaska - Radiation, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albany - Troy Fallout. Articles, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albany - Troy. Low Dose Rate (1967 Draft). Backr'd. Drafts, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Aliquippa Hearing Story (Joel's), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aliquippa Hospital Administration. Article, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Aliquippa Testimony. Extra Copy (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Allegheny County. Health and Pollution. Statistics and Officials, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alpha Particles. Doses, Theory, Biological Effects, Natural Sources. Trinity Area, 1957-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alpha Radiation to Lung. Dose from Natural Levels. Lung Cancer, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alternative Energy Sources - I, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Alternative Energy Sources - II, 1971-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Alternatives to Growth, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Alvarez, Luis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Alvarez, Robert, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Alvarez, robert. Environmental Policy Center. Kitty Tucker - I, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Alvarez, robert. Environmental Policy Center. Kitty Tucker - II, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS). Constitution and Comments, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Association of Physicists in Medicine (AAPM). Attack and Answer 1971, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Medical Association (AMA) Pro-Nuclear State (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Nuclear Society (ANS), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Public Health Association, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Amsterdam Conference 87, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Anchovy Crisis. Peru. Radiation Effects., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ancient Civilizations. Symias. Positive Evidence of Advanced Scholarly Knowledge or Extraterrestrial Visitors, 1975-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Antiballistic Missile (ABM) Battle. History and Treaty, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Antiballistic Missile Defense. Leser. Particle Beams, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Anti-Nuclear Books, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Anti-Nuclear Movement. Pro-Lifers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Anti-Nuclear Movements, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Anti-Nuclear News Clippings - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Anti-Nuclear Publications. Minnesota, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Anti-Nuclear Rebellion. Japan and USA, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Anti-Nuclear Weapons and War Movie, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Apollo Parks Township. Documents, 1966-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arms Control. History of (Including Role of JFK, Kruch, etc.) - I, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arms Control. History of (Including Role of JFK, Kruch, etc.) - II, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Arms Control. Nuclear Weapons Debate. Tactics and First Strike, 1974-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Arno's Work, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Arterial Disease and Stroke Decline, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Arteriosclerosis. Alpha Radiation. Experiments, Plans. Recorded Materials in Animals and Man, 1960-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Articles. Possible Plans; Journals '80, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Aspden, H, 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Asthma Mortality, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Atomic Bomb, Origin of, Casualty Commission Study, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Atomic Bomb History. Manhattan project. Radiological Hazard, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Atomic Bomb History (See Also Nuclear Web). Nuclear Age. Battle Over Effects With [AEC] NY State Health Department, 1970-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) and Nuclear Industry Attack on Me, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Propaganda and Attacks On, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Atomic Soldiers. Quigley Case, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Attacks by Utility. Arguments for Nuclear Power, 1970-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Australia and French Tests, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Austrian Anti-Nuclear Group, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Automobile (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Axelrod, Patricia. Hero Project, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Babcock and Wilcox. Nuclear Waste Incinerator Plan 1984, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Background Radiation Effects, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Backscattering of Electrons, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Baneberry, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Baneberry Test and Other Underground Leaks, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Baum, J. W., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Baumgardt, 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Baumgardt, David. Baader Letters, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Baumgardt, David. Correspondence, Last Arrangements, 1960-1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Baumgardt David S Birthday, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Beaver valey 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Beaver Valley. Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Internal Documents, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Beaver Valley Battle. Goldman Testimony, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Stephen, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Berkeley Conference july, 71, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bertell, Rosalie J, 1975-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Beyea, Jan. Papers, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Beyea, J. Three Mile Island Study, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Big-Rock Nuclear Plant Studies, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bikini-Braud Study Data, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Biological Effects of Ionizing Radiations (BEIR) Committee. July 18, 1977 Hearing (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bird Reproduction. Effects on, Mech. Data. Also See "Terns", 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bogart, Larry, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bogart, Larry Groups (Including New England Coal, National Cimmittee to Stop Environmental Pollution), 1970-1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Boiling Water Reactors (BWR). General Electric Company (GE) Releases, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bone Mineral Measurements, 1962-1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bone Scanning. Sandler 1982-1983, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Book Burning Evidence, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Book Documentation. Childhood Leukemia. "Science" Article Correspondence, 1962-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Book. Material for Conclusion, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Book on Origin of Universe Ideas, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Brain Cancer and Radiation Data (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Brain, Function, Organization, Etc., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Brain Functions. Cognition, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Brain and Nerve Action Mechanism; For Radiation Damage, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Breeder Reactor, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Brodsky, A. Papers, 1965-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bross, 1968-1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bross. Testimony (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brower, Dave. Foe Battle, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Brown. Long Distance Radiation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Budget. University of Pittsburg Radiation Research Engineers, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scietists Articles, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bureau of Radiological Health, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bureau of Radiological Health - 1971 Report, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Businessmen for the Public Interest (BPI), 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - C-14 Oak Ridge Effects, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Caldicott, Helen, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Caldwell, Lynton C, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Caldwell, Roger, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - California Fallout Episode (LA 1958) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - California Initiative, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Calvert Cliffs (Shows Higs Sr90 + Viol), 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Canada. Infant Mortality Sr-90, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Canada Nuclear Program. Leukemia, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Canadian Nuclear Opposition, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Canadian Reactor Release, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Cancer. Age Specific. Beaver and Near (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Cancer. Biological Mechanisms, Promoters, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Cancer of the Breast, 1965-1976 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Cancer, Cervical (Baltimore), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Cancer, Childhood, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Cancer. Cover-up of Epidemic, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Cancer. Geographic Patterns. Esophaegal Cancer in Irand and Asia, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Cancer and Immune System. Free Radicals, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Cancer In Industry. UAW Booklet, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Cancer and Louisiana Water Supply, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Cancer. Lung, 1963-1977 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Cancer Mortality. World Wide Patterns vs. Males, SEGI (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Cancer. Relations to Natural Background. Archer, V. Low Level Radiation and Environment (Cosmic), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Cancer, Risk (Doubling Dose), 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Cancer Risk Estimates. Chem. Dose Rate (Mays, Gofman), 1968-1978 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Cancer. Skin, UV, Sun, 1965-1975 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Cancer. Synchronized Action With Virus Infection. Childhood Cancers, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cancer. Theory and Early Detection. Government Research Program, 1967-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Canonsburg PA, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Casarett, G. W. Cancer Mechanisms, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Carcinogens. Chemical and Radiation Mechanisms (Andelman), 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Carnow Letter, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Carter, Jimmy 7/15/76, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Catholic Bishops 1983 Statement on Nuclear War Morality (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cattle and Calf Disease Data, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cattle and Calf Disease and Sr-90, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cattle and Calves. Radiation Effects on Health, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cell Function and Control. Synchronization and Biological Clock, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cember Study. Infant Mortality (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cesium-137. Dose Estimates in US, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Characteristic Energy Losses, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Charge Energy Losses. Solids as Collections of Atoms. New Theory, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chemical Exposure. Toxicity Tests, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chemical Waste Control, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - China. Birth Drop and Bomb Tests (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chinese Fallout. Infant Mortality. October 1976, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chinese Test. Fallout Data 1976, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Christic Institute, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Chromosomal Effects of Radiation (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cincinnati Paper on Environmental Health, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cincinnati UF6 Plant Relocation (Tom Applegate, Channel 9, TV Cinc.) 513-721-9900, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Circle - Peace Group Organization, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Citizens Advisory Council, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Citizens" Environmental Task Force (Madoff), 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Civil Defense and Cancer Incidence Reduction (1981) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Coal Radioactivity. Hydrocarbons and Particles Data, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Coal vs. Nuclear Risks, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Cohen, B. Testimony, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Cold War Origins. German Nazi Scientists in US, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Colorado. Uranium Mills Gas Discharge, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Color TV. Radioactive Effects, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Columbia Reactor. 1979 Hearing (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Columbia University Reactor. Hearing Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Columbia University. Triga, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Columbia University. Triga Reactor. Testimony, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Common Cause, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Commoner, B, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Computed Tomography (CT) Scanning. History, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Computer Programs, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Computerized Electronic Radiography (CER), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Computerized Electronic Radiography. Patent Draft, 1965-1976 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Congenital Defects and Blindness - I, 1957-1971 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Congenital Defects and Blindness - II, 1961-1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Congenital Defects. Brain and Nervous System Development, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Congenital Defects. Cognition and Radiation, 1965-1987 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Congenital Defects. Effects of Low-Level Radiation. Mental Illness, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Congenital Defects. Fallout. Crime Rise, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Congenital Defects. Learning Ability. Chemical Basis, 1963-1977 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Congenital Defects and Mental Abilities. Education Trends in US. Youth Unemployment, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Congenital Defects; Mental Health and Radiation; Suicide; Crime; SAT, etc. - I, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Congenital Defects; Mental Health and Radiation; Suicide; Crime; SAT, etc. - II, 1968-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Congenital Defects Mortality US. (Rise in 1979) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Congenital Defects and Radiation - I, 1967-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Congenital Defects and Radiation - II, 1967-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Congenital Malfunction. Mortality and Fallout. PA, etc., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Congenital Retardation. SAT and Radiation. Orlando Paper 1979, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Action. Ideas For., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Record. Public. Related to Nuclear Hazard and Infant Mortality, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Seminar 1976. Low-Level Radiation (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Seminar 1976. Notes (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Seminar. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Seminar on Radiation. May 4, 1976. My Testimony and That of Others, 1970-1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Congress, US. Composition, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut. Cancer, 1977-1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut Cancer. Incidence by Age (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Connecticut. Cancer - Millstone I Radiation Environmental Protection, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Connecticut. Cancer and Other Data (Millstone Controversy) and Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut Cancer Regulation Data, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut. Cancer Study - Windsor Site, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Connecticut Data (Helen Kennedy), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Connecticut (Millstone) Infant Mortality. Total Mortality, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut and New York State. Millstone Data, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Connecticut Nuclear Plant Effects - Waterford Area Data. Yearly Visit Statistics Sumary. Research for Book II, 1978-1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Connecticut. Reactor Study. Plots, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Contrast Media - Iodine Toxicity and Increased Radiation Dose, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cooling Accident. Hearings, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence and Clippings (Unsorted) 1974 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Cosmology and Particles Clippings and Articles. 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Cost-Benefit of Radiation Control, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Cousteau, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Creativity, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Crib Death. Sudden Infant Death (SID), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Crime (Juvenile) and Brain Damage from Radiation, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Critical Mass, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Critics of Atomic Energy Commission (AEC). Miscellaneous. Merz, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Curry, Bill. The Washington Post, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Davis Besse. Environmental Hearing Test. Graphs, 1964-1973 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Davis Besse. Original Test, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Degel, Jim, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - DeGroot. Information on Mortality, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - DeGroot. Plans for Radiation Effects and Infant Mortality Study. DeGroot Paper, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Denenberg Hearings, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Diabetes and Fallout, 1971-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Diabetes and Radiation (Milk). Scientific American. October 1992, p24. John Rennie (Dr. Hans-Michael Dosch, Toronto) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Diablo Canyon Battle 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Diagnostic Radiology. Electronic and Computer Technology, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Diagnostic X-Ray Doses, Past and Present. Chest, etc., 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Diagnostic X-Ray Exposure and Dose Reduction Techniques, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Diode Digital Radiography - 1996, 1971-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Disease Control, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Dose, Doubling Rate Effect; Dose-Respective Curve, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dose Reduction in Radiology. Morgan K. Z., 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dose-Respective Curves; Dose-Rate Effects, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dosimetry. Dose in Diagnostics, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Dresden; Annual Environmental Report 71-76, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Dresden II and Relevant Papers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Dresden. Water Born Effects., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dublin Paper. Draft, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Dublin Paper. Final Type-Script (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Dumand 1975, 1965-1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Duquesne Light, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Dyson, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Eagle Feather. Book Plans 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - ECO, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Ecologist," the Article on Survival, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Eddington, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Einstein and Philosophy of Physics, 1947-1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Two letters (typed, signed) from Albert Einstein, one discussing Sternglass's overemphasis on Kant and the importance of terminology in dictating thought. The second related to the voltage necessary to create a neutron from an electron. Also, some newspaper clippings mentioning Einstein and Sternglass and a copy of a letter from Louis de Broglie to an unknown individual (found amongst the Einstein letters)., 1947-1963 (Box MS 72, Folder 6842m)
  - Eisenbud, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Electronic Imaging in Radiology, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Electronic Mammography, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Electronic Radiography. Cervicocerebrovascular Angiography. National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI), 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Electronic Radiography. Chest and Coronary. Real Time. 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Electronic Radiography Diode (NCI-1976) Reference Materials, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Electronic Radiography. Drafts, 1962-1973 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Electronic Radiography. Monochromal Radiation. 1975 Developments and Plants., 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Electronic Radiography. Papers, Plans, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Electronic Radiography. Theory, 1971-1983 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Embryonic and Fetal Development (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS). Possible Failures, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - EMI Scanner, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Energy Crisis and Food Crisis I, 1971-1977 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Energy Crisis and Food Crisis II, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Energy Parks, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Environmental Action and Other Environmental Groups I, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Environmental Action and Other Environmental Groups II, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Environmental Monitoring Instructions and Standards, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Hearing. References. Aging, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Radiation Data. Sr-90, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Radiation Standards Hearing - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Radiation Standards. Testing 1976. March 10, 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Radiation From Fallout. Gibson et al., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Radiation. Man-Made and Natural Sources, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Radiation. Milk, Diet, etc., 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Review Paper, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Environment Paper Material. Radiation Environmental Pollution., 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Erie Nuclear Reactor (1978) (Stebbins; Cleveland), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Eskimos, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Eskimo Study and Nuclear Fallout 1981, 1968-1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Esquire Article (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ethical and Moral Basis of Science, 1964-1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - European Anti-Nuclear Movement I, 1971-1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - European Anti-Nuclear Movement II, 1974-1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - European Anti-Nuclear Movement III, 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Evolution and Morphogenesis Theory, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Evolution Theory. Darwinian and Other, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)